

Profile

I am a dynamic business oriented, Saudi national, interested in enhancing the use of technology in our daily lives. Worked on several projects in many fields, i.e., Physical Security, ERP Systems, E-commerce, IT Manpower Recruiting and IT Service Management.

Contact

- ★ 13221 Riyadh, Saudi Arabia
- **1** +966 53 5460 203
- ✓ faris.suliman1994@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/farisdowayraat

Personal information

Name

Faris Suliman Ali Dowayraat

Birthdate

9 Nov 1994

Nationality

Saudi

Martial Status

Single

Languages

Arabic English



FARIS SULIMAN

IT Service Management Specialist

Experience

Command Center Analyst

HCL Technologies | Nov 2020 - Present

Client: Ministry Of Finance / National Center for Government Resources

- Monitoring and handling alerts in the real time.
- · Analyzing the severity of the incidents.
- Proactive reporting.
- Connecting teams through a bridge call to resolve major incidents.
- · Drafting daily reports.
- Ensuring that all SLAs are met.

Administrative Assistant

Jomla | Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

- · Documentation.
- Providing support for the customers.
- Updating products information.
- Data entry.

ERP Junior Functional Specialist

Open Technologies | May 2019 - Mar 2020

- · Analyzing clients requirements.
- · Odoo databases testing.
- Assisting in creating user manuals and business proposals.
- · Conducting user training.

Software Developer

Open Technologies | Apr 2019 - Aug 2019

Designing and developing Odoo applications and modules.

Help Desk Support

Construction & Development LTD. | Jun 2017 - Aug 2017 Practical training that focused on providing an IT support to the employees.

Education

Bachelor in Information Systems

Al-Imam Muhammad Ibn Saud University, Riyadh | Sep 2012 - May 2018

Certification

Axelos

ITIL® 4 Foundation Certificate in ITSM

Effective from: 29 Jun 2022 Certificate ID: GR671412320FD

Faris Suliman

Skills

IT Service Management Odoo ERP System System Analysis & Documentation Quality Control

Programming Languages

Python C++HTML5 \ CSS3 Java Script PHP



Projects

Feb 2017 -**Tile Security System (TSS)** Dec 2017 College of Computer & Information Sciences

Worked within a team to accomplish a graduation project (Non-Commercial) in the field of physical security.

End of Service Reward Calculator Jun 2019

Open Technologies

Motivational Task: My manager challenged me to write a program that calculates the end of service reward (in Python). I have done it, I have applied all the cases correctly according to the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Development calculator.

Jun 2019 -**Odoo ERP System Implementation**

Jan 2020 Client: Enjaz Co. Role: Junior Functional Specialist

Duties:

· Requirements analysis and documentation.

• Assisting in the demonstration process of the system.

· System errors detection.

• Translating the terms to Arabic.

• Creating user manuals for the desired modules.

• Training the users to use the system.

Jan 2020 -**IT ManPower Recruitment**

Mar 2020 Client: Accenture

Role: Recruitment Assistant

Duties:

Assisting in the candidates selection process.

· Filtering candidates' resumes.

· Screening the candidates.

• Scheduling job interviews to the candidates

Courses

ITIL 4 Foundation Nov 2021

Ministry of Communication & IT, Online Course

Sep 2021

Ministry of Communication & IT , Online Course

PHP Web Development Sep 2020 -

DSC Jazan University, Online Course Oct 2020

BlockChain Strategist Jul 2020 -

Software Development Academy, Online Course Oct 2020

CCNA - CCNA Security - ITIL 3 Dec 2018 -

Ministry of Communication & IT, Riyadh Jan 2019

Full Stack Developer May 2018 -

Udacity, Online Course Nov 2018

IBM SPSS Workshop Apr 2017 College of Computer & Information Sciences, Riyadh